Contact

07842178720 (Work) ac.will.dev@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/cathrinwill (LinkedIn) acwill.dev/ (Portfolio)

Top Skills

Sanity Next.js

Vanilla JavaScript

Languages

English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Native or Bilingual)

Certifications

Tech Career Skills: Moving from Developer to Engineering Manager

Ann-Cathrin Will

Senior Frontend Developer

Warfield, England, United Kingdom

Summary

I'm an experienced Frontend Developer that has worked at a variety of digital and marketing agencies for over 12~ years.

I have strong core skills in writing semantic, accessibility-friendly HTML, and modular, modern CSS using a mix of SCSS and tailwind. Over the years I have experienced a few flavours of JavaScript, my favourite being vanilla and React.js, but I was around for the jQuery days and I've nibbled on vue.js.

Lately I've been enjoying getting more into Sanity CMS for my web builds as it is a fast solution with a lot of flexibility, and I've been using Next.js for a few years now so that pairs well. That said I've experienced a variety of CMS-enabled e-commerce and marketing sites, working closely with backend developers, and creative teams from conception to deployment.

Experience

Rawnet Digital Agency

7 years

Head of UI

September 2022 - Present (2 years)

- Promoted the adoption of React/Next.js for building dynamic, responsive, and user-centric web applications, driving innovation in front-end architecture.
- Collaborated closely with backend developers and creative teams to develop CMS-driven e-commerce and marketing websites, overseeing projects from inception to launch.
- Utilised Semantic HTML, modular SCSS, Tailwind CSS, and vanilla
 JavaScript to ensure accessibility and maintainability, adhering to industry standards and best practices.

- Developed and maintained a front-end boilerplate, streamlining the development process and ensuring consistency across multiple projects.
- Enhanced Developer Experience (DX) by integrating modern tools, workflows, and automation, leading to improved efficiency and code quality.
- Advanced from Mid-weight Frontend Developer to Head of UI, demonstrating strong leadership and technical expertise.
- Led and mentored a team of front-end developers, establishing coding standards, promoting best practices, and fostering a collaborative and innovative work environment.

UI Lead Developer
June 2020 - September 2022 (2 years 4 months)

Senior UI Developer September 2019 - June 2020 (10 months) Ascot, UK

UI Developer September 2017 - September 2019 (2 years 1 month) Ascot, Berkshire, United Kingdom

The Purple Agency
Frontend Web Developer
March 2013 - August 2017 (4 years 6 months)
Basingstoke

- Built responsive front-end websites from Photoshop designs using SCSS/ LESS and task runners like grunt/gulp
- Developed and set up email campaigns to support marketing initiatives
- Ensured websites were accessibility-friendly and compliant with WCAG standards
- Implemented semantic code, meta/micro data, and Google Analytics for SEO enhancement
- Utilised Git, Bitbucket, Sourcetree, and SVN for version control.

Webexpectations
Frontend Web Developer
September 2012 - March 2013 (7 months)
Slough, United Kingdom

- Developed front-end code from Photoshop templates for standalone pages used in multivariate testing
- Specialised in responsive web development and optimised for mobile and retina displays
- Created HTML emails and HTML email signatures.

Premier Inn
Night Receptionist
September 2009 - September 2012 (3 years 1 month)
Cobham, Surrey, United Kingdom

Weekend job throughout attending University.

superReal GmbH | Agentur für Neue Kommunikation Frontend Web Developer (Intern) April 2007 - October 2007 (7 months) Hamburg Area, Germany

Work experience in Hamburg learning how to make websites, working with Graphic Designers and Backend Developers. Taking extra care to make websites identical across browsers including such challenges as IE6/7 and the box model bug.

Education

Kingston University
Web Development with Business BSc (Hons), Web
Development · (2009 - 2012)

Kingston College
Foundation degree, Computer Information Systems and
Mathematics · (2008 - 2009)

Langley Grammar GCSE · (1999 - 2004)